[Music]
in searching for the latest and greatest
science on vinegar I came across this
study on lime juice and vinegar
injections as a cheap and natural
alternative to control cots outbreaks I
was all intrigued until I realized cots
stands for crown of thorn sea star those
crazy looking
starfish but just when I thought that
was an unusual title to pee or not to
pee a review on jellyfish inv venim and
treatment due to an increase in
jellyfish blooms jellyfish inv venim has
become an increasing public health
problem amounting to as many as 150
million jellyfish stings every year but
no research does not support the use of
the most infamous sting treatment urine
is unclear exactly when the use of urine
for jellyfish stings became popular
though certainly the scene from friends
didn't help but it has become one of the
most persistent myths in
toxicology what does help the topical
application of vinegar for 30 seconds
may be effective any other conditions
where topical vinegar may help what
about for eczema also known as atopic
dermatitis not only did dilute vinegar
soaks yield no benefit it caused
substantial adverse effects skin
irritation in the majority of
subjects okay scratch that what about
topical vinegar for ureic partis one of
the most common disabling symptoms in
patients with endstage kidney disease
it's a chronic itching Sensation that
frequently accompanies chronic kidney
disease you could imagine how it could
cause depression insomnia anxiety so
these researchers tried randomizing
sufferers to try applying an oatmeal
ition or dilute vinegar about 1 tbspoon
per cup of water versus taking an
anti-histamine drug The Oatmeal Lotion
significantly reduce the intensity of
itching but not the frequency or Surface
area affected whereas both the vinegar
and the drug accomplished all
three what else what about a randomized
control trial on the effect of topical
apple cider vinegar on varicose veins
between 25 and 50% of adults have
varicose veins in their legs which can
be more than just an aesthetic concern
varicose veins can cause pain swelling
cramps irritability fatigue itching
tingling burning a heavy feeling
bleeding and even ulceration what can we
do about them apple cider vinegar which
is known to have legit healing
properties is stressed in many websites
to help but you don't know until you put
it to the test patients were randomized
to apply vinegar to the affected area of
the leg now here are the before and
after symptoms in the the vinegar group
versus the control group those in the
vinegar group appear to do better than
the control group but the whole point of
having a control group is to directly
compare the groups to each other not to
where they started before and after
comparisons against Baseline within
randomized groups is a common
statistical mistake that can be highly
misleading biased and invalid so we
really don't know if apple cider vegar
works better than nothing after all and
there are potential risks a 14-year-old
girl presented with two erosions on her
nose she found something on the Internet
about using vinegar to remove moles and
removed part of her nose
instead I don't recommend applying
undiluted vinegar to your skin and you
should never drink it straight which can
land you in the emergency room vomiting
blood with an esophagus that looks like
this the only time I'd consider using
straight vinegar is in tiny doses up the
nose in nasal vinegar as an effective
treatment for persistent hiccups in a
patient with Advanced cancer undergoing
pallative care persistent intractable
hiccups are normally rare however in
patients with Advanced cancer it can
affect like one in 25 it's bad enough
you're dying from cancer but then to
have unending hiccups keeping you awake
or preventing you from connecting with
your loved ones so they tried a very
small amount of vinegar and by very
small we're talking two drops
this is what it looks like just two
little drops at the tip of a needleless
syringe and the patient's hiccups
resolved within a few seconds what they
think is going on is the same nerve
route that goes to the nose also goes to
the hiccup area and the irritation is
thought to then interrupt the hiccup
reflex in the past nonpharmacological
remedies such as vinegar were largely
used for this kind of thing but then
they fell out of favor with the
widespread use of drugs which in in this
case were ineffective
[Music]